# **Daniel French**

# College Station, TX | 832.316.7138 | dan.r.french@sbcglobal.net | LinkedIn

# Summary

I have a passion for learning, solving problems and analyzing information. I have professional experience building and managing responsive client websites using WordPress, as well as creating child themes to modify theme plugins for custom features. I also have a solid understanding of object-oriented programming with C#.

# **Experience**

## Centennial Arts | Software Developer

January 2024 - Present

- Designed and built customer websites using WordPress
- Installed and managed WordPress packages and plugins on FreeBSD operating system
- Logged and communicated progress on customer websites and other issues using Jira
- Created child themes to modify theme plugin files for custom features
- Curated plugins for situational use
- Debugged plugins and submitted bug reports on GitHub for future releases
- Documented new processes in Confluence for collecting website content, plugin setup and usage, child theme directory structure and usage, and managing core WordPress settings

## Real Estate Agent | Keller Williams Realty Brazos Valley

**April 2021 – October 2023** 

- Marketed our services through social media, direct mail campaigns and outbound phone calls
- Prepared and presented pricing analyses and marketing strategies to prospective listing clients
- Showed properties to prospective buyers
- Maintained transaction paperwork such as contract addenda, listing agreements, buyer's representation agreements, etc.

#### Courier | FedEx Express

October 2010 - April 2023

- Responsible for safely and efficiently sorting and delivering packages in College Station and surrounding areas
- Led the team responsible for receiving and delivering First Overnight packages
- Supervised unloading activities and ensured a successful flow rate of packages per hour

# **Education**

#### True Coders Full Stack Software Engineering Program

**Graduated July 2023** 

- Project based training in programming languages and other technical skills, such as SQL,
  C#, .NET Core, Git, ASP.NET, MVC, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Skills were developed by building multiple C# and SQL projects in Visual and Visual Studio Code
- C# and SQL Projects were tracked in Git and GitHub for source control
- Managed SQL databases using CRUD operations in MySQL

### B.B.A in Marketing, Texas A&M University-Kingsville

**Graduated December 2008** 

- Gained a solid foundation in marketing principles such as market research, consumer behavior and market segmentation
- · Learned personal sales skills and techniques
- Learned strategies for market entry and analyzing strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats in competitive markets
- Accounting Principles
- Graduated with honors (3.6 G.P.A.)

# **Skills & abilities**

- WordPress
- HTML
- CSS
- MySQL
- C#

# Links

- LinkedIn
- GitHub
- Portfolio